Okay, so lesson two
covers the basic foundational
concepts of project management, right?
And that's really what
you're going to be learning
in this lesson, just some
of the basic foundations.
So let's just cover some of the learning
objectives then.
Now, what this really
refers to essentially
is chapters one to three of Pimbok, right?
Pinbock Guide version 6, just really
chapters one to three.
And these are just the basic foundations,
the basic framework, the building blocks,
if you like, of project management,
the ABCs of project management.
The rest of the syllabus,
the rest of the class is
going to build upon
these basic building blocks.
So we're going to be covering the basic
framework, the basic foundations,
such as defining a project.
I want to talk about the definition of a
project, definition of project management.
Along with this, we're going to be talking
about things like progressive elaboration.
We're going to be introducing enterprise
environmental factors and organizational
process asset and how they interact with
each other, how they affect the project,
how constraints affect the project.
We'll talk about the
roles, the basic roles on a
project, structures of
different organizations.
These all fall under the basic framework,
the basic foundations.
Plus, we're going to talk about the
different types of project life cycles,
such as iterative life
cycle and incremental,
right, and of course
it's predictive and agile.
Remember, 50% of the exam is predictive.
50% is agile and hybrid.
And predictive and agile are two almost
conflicting views of project management.
So you need to recognize the difference
between them.
And so overall, you need to understand the
PMI framework.
You need to understand PMI standards.
Right.
So you need to appreciate
the standards of project
management as it relates to
PMI as it relates to Pembuck.